# **Charles Vinoth**

# Front-End Developer

Email. Phone. Portfolio. GitHub.

charlezvinoth@gmail.com +91-7010034120 charlesvinoth.com github.com/charlesvinoth

#### **Profile**

Front-End developer with more than 4 years of experience designing and developing responsive web and mobile applications. Proficient in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript frameworks with a thorough understanding of UI and UX. Notable accomplishments include an 80% increase in the sales of an existing product through improved design and code.

## **Experience**

### Senior Front-End Developer @ ezofis

Sep 2021 - Present // Tirunelveli, Tamilnadu, India

- Designed and built modern, scalable, responsive, distributed cloud-based applications using Vue.js and React.js.
- Delivered complex UX/UI components without compromising quality and speed.
- Led a team of 4 developers through building multiple Vue.js and React.js applications.
- o Built and shipped 2 robust apps to Android/iOS devices using Dart and Flutter.
- o Followed SDLC best practices within an Agile environment to produce rapid iterations for clients.
- o Experienced in working with IIS web servers, Netlify and Azure, and Firebase.
- Collaborated with developers, managers, and clients during development processes to confirm proposals and design best practices.

#### Front-End Developer @ ezofis

Sep 2019 - Aug 2021 // Tirunelveli, Tamilnadu, India

- o Conceptualized, designed, and developed several apps using React.js, Vue.js, etc.
- o Crafted a solid design system to enforce consistency across the application.
- Translated designs and wireframes into a highly responsive user interface and reusable components.
- Performed user experience and quality assurance testing to identify and remedy shortcomings.
- o Introduced and enforced healthy codebases, coding styles, and standards.
- o Interfaced with clients every week, providing technological expertise and knowledge.
- o Analyzed business requirements, and participated in technical design, development, and testing of various modules assigned.

## Junior Front-End Developer @ ezofis

Nov 2018 – Aug 2019 // Tirunelveli, Tamilnadu, India

- o Written modern, performant, and robust code for a diverse array of clients and internal projects.
- Made recommendations for new technology integration based on suitability and alignment with business goals.
- Removed jQuery and jQuery plugins and replaced them with vanilla JavaScript, which increased the application speed by 50%.
- o Communicated effectively with project managers and the team to complete projects on time and deliver to clients accordingly.
- Introduced and used Git and GitHub to manage the source code.
- o Replaced XML with JSON as API payload which increased the application speed by 20%.

## **Skills**

Proficient-HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6+), Vue.js, Vuex, Vue Router, Vue CLI, Quasar.js, Bootstrap, TailwindExperienced-Sass, React.js, Node.js, Material Design, Dart, Flutter, Git, GitHub, Bulma, NPM, Jest, Cypress, PiniaFamiliar-Redux, React Router, jQuery, PostgreSQL, Python, Netlify, Firebase, Azure, Postman, VS Code, Vite

## **Education**

## **B.E Computer Science and Engineering**

National College of Engineering, Tirunelveli, Tamilnadu